Guide to the Dorothy Allison Papers, 1965-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Subject Files Series, 1974-1998 and undated, (31 boxes)
  - Subject Files Subseries, Non-alphabetical
    - Fowler, Connie Mae (Box 31)
    - Croce, Arlene - AIDS plays (Box 31)
    - Seajay, Carol (Box 31)
    - hooks, bell (Box 31)
    - Paglia, Camille (Box 31)
    - Brown, Rebecca (Box 31)
    - Fuller and Langerman Gym - Sebastopol (Box 31)
    - Estes, Clarissa Pinkola (Box 31)
    - Smiley, Jane, on Huck Finn (Box 31)
    - Djerassi (Box 31)
    - Allure Magazine (Box 31)
    - Feminist bookstores (Box 31)
- Chronological Files Series, 1975-2009 and undated, (65 boxes)
  These files contain chiefly correspondence, copies of Allison's articles, some research files, clippings, and fiction by other writers.
  Collection Arrangement
  Allison's original chronological order has been retained.
  - 1975-1979 (Box 32)
  - 1980-1982 (Box 33)
  - 1982-1985 (Box 34)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 35)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 36)
  - 1986-1988 (Box 37)
  - 1989-1991 (Box 38)
  - 1991-1993 (Box 39)
  - 1992-1993 (Box 40-42)
  - Clippings, 1980s-1990s and undated (Box 43-44)
  - 1992-1997 (Box 45)
  - 1984-1993 (Box 46)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 47-49)
  - 1995 (Box 50-52)
  - 1995-1996 (Box 53)
  - 1996 (Box 54-56)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 57)
  - 1996-2004 (Box 58)
  - 1997 (Box 59-61)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 62-63)
  - 1998 (Box 64)
  - 1997-2003 (Box 65)
  - 1997 (Box 66)
  - 1998 (Box 67-68)
  - 1999 (Box 69-71)
  - 2000 (Box 72)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 73-75)
  - 2000 (Box 76-77)
  - 2001 (Box 78)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 79)
  - 2002 (Box 80-81)
  - 2002-2004 (Box 82)
  - 2003 (Box 83)
  - 2004 (Box 84)
  - 2005 (Box 85)
  - 2006 (Box 86)
  - 2005-2006 (Box 87)
  - 2003-2004 (Box 88)
  - 2005 (Box 89)
  - 2005-2006 (Box 90)
  - 2002 (Box 91)
  - 2006-2007 (Box 92)
  - 2007 (Box 93)
  - 2008 (Box 94)
  - 2008-2009 (Box 95)
  - 2009 (Box 96)
- Travel, Work and Appearances Series, 1977-2010, (22 boxes)
  These materials document Allison's professional life, travel, and appearances.
  - Royalties (Box 97)
  - 1977-1995 (Box 98)
  - 1988-1992 (Box 99)
  - 1992-1996 (Box 100)
  - 1992-2005 (Box 101)
  - 1993-1996 (Box 102)
  - 1994-1997 (Box 103)
  - 1995-1996 (Box 104)
  - 1995-2002 (Box 105)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 106)
  - 1997-2004 (Box 107)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 108)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 109)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 110)
  - 2001 (Box 111)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 112)
  - 2003-2004 (Box 113)
  - 2004-2005 (Box 114)
  - 2005-2006 (Box 115)
  - 2006-2007 (Box 116)
  - 2008 (Box 117)
  - 2009-2010 (Box 118)
- Writings Series, 1982-2008 and undated, (45 boxes)
  This series contains drafts of Allison's unpublished and published works as well as her personal journals, which are restricted and require permission from the creator prior to use.
  This series also contains Allison's unpublished writings, which require written permission from their creator for access and copying.
  RESTRICTED: Access to Allison's unpublished writings in boxes 122, 122a, and 123 are restricted and require written permission from their creator for access and copying.
  Allison's original order and folder titles have been retained.
  - Bastard Out of Carolina manuscript (2 folders) (Box 119)
  - Themes/science fiction (Box 119)
  - Introduction to deviant ethnography (Box 119)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina proof (Box 120)
  - Anne Lamott broadside (Box 120)
  - The Writer's Chronicle, May/Summer 2001, October/November 2002 (Box 120)
  - Fliers (Box 120)
  - Cavedweller covers (Box 120)
  - The Ultimate Lesbian Fantasy (Box 120)
  - Fiction: first draft (Box 120)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina draft (Box 121)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina notes (Box 121)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina manuscript (Box 121)
  - Gospel drafts (Box 121)
  - Gospel Song (Box 121)
  - Gospel Song long version (Box 121)
  - Two or Three Things I Know for Sure proofs with corrections (Box 121)
  - The Women Who Hate Me 1st complete draft (Box 121)
  - The Women Who Hate Me draft (Box 121)
  - Cavedweller (Box 121)
  - Unpublished short stories (RESTRICTED) (Box 122-123)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina drafts (Box 124-126)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina bound typescript (Box 127-128)
  - Trash typescripts (Box 127-128)
  - Cavedweller drafts (Box 129-134)
  - Cavedweller chapter list, short stories and bound typescript (2 folders) (Box 135)
  - Conference materials, Women's Caucus for Art, 1992 (Box 135)
  - Skin draft (Box 135)
  - Short stories (Box 135)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina audiobook script (Box 136)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina draft script (Box 136)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina revised draft script (Box 136)
  - The Lammas Little Review (Box 137)
  - Review: Anne Lamott All New People (Box 137)
  - A Lesbian Appetite (Box 137)
  - Review of The Lost Languages of Cranes (Box 137)
  - Ursula LeGuin: Dancing at the Edge of the World Village Voice (Box 137)
  - Women in Love for Ikon Magazine (Box 137)
  - Lupus (Box 137)
  - Lupus (Box 137)
  - Death and the Bag Man (Box 137)
  - Mama (Box 137)
  - The meanest woman ever left Tennessee (Box 137)
  - Modern Primitives, RE/Search #12, Village Voice review (Box 137)
  - Monkeybites (Box 137)
  - My Career as a Thief (Box 137)
  - The muscles of the mind (Box 137)
  - Myths, Images, and the Creation of Reality essay (Box 137)
  - Never Satisfied, Village Voice review (Box 137)
  - There are only 99 lesbians (Box 137)
  - North (Box 137)
  - Not as a stranger (Box 137)
  - Joyce Carol Oates review (Box 137)
  - On Our Backs review (Box 137)
  - Passion Fruit review (Box 137)
  - Personal Best (Box 137)
  - Gone to Soldiers Marge Piercy (Box 137)
  - Cave Dweller (Box 137)
  - A Question of Censorship (Box 137)
  - Changing the World (Box 137)
  - Skin drafts (Box 138)
  - Two or Three Things drafts (Box 138)
  - Two or Three Things drafts (Box 139)
  - Mean Stories and Stubborn Girls draft (Box 140)
  - Cavedweller abridgement (Box 140)
  - Cavedweller (2 folders) (Box 140)
  - Trash proofs (Box 140)
  - Lost Friend, Loss, Nice, The Men in My Family are Awful (Box 140)
  - Coffee Shop (Box 141)
  - Deciding to Live (Box 141)
  - Demon (Box 141)
  - Demon Lover (Box 141)
  - Don't Tell Me You Don't Know (Box 141)
  - Epidemiology of Stigma (Box 141)
  - Erotic Blasphemy (Box 141)
  - Her Thighs (Box 141)
  - I'm Working on My Charm (Box 141)
  - Obscene Every Moment (Box 141)
  - Something Else (Box 141)
  - Puritans, Perverts and Feminists (Box 141)
  - Fire and Ice (Box 141)
  - Jesus (Box 141)
  - Politically Incorrect (Box 141)
  - Living in the Evil City (Box 141)
  - Conceptual Lesbianism (Box 141)
  - Personal History of Porn (Box 141)
  - The Way to a Lesbian Heart (Box 141)
  - Two or Three Things ... (Box 142)
  - Steal Away (Box 142)
  - Compassion (Box 142)
  - Mama Died (Box 142)
  - Anonymous Letters (Box 142)
  - Bastards Make Their Own Rules (Box 142)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina (Box 142)
  - Biscuit Dinners (Box 142)
  - The Body in Context (Box 142)
  - Boston, Massachusetts (Box 142)
  - Nasty (Box 142)
  - Cave Dweller (Box 142)
  - Private Rituals (2 folders) (Box 143)
  - Premises (Box 143)
  - The Psychic (Box 143)
  - Public Silence, Private Terror (Box 143)
  - A Question of Class (Box 143)
  - The Hard Logic of Love (Box 143)
  - Rewriting Our Lives (Box 143)
  - River of Names (Box 143)
  - Skin (Box 143)
  - Two Faggots, 20 Dykes and a Whole Lot of Barbeque (Box 143)
  - Violence Against Women Begins at Home (Box 143)
  - What She Did With Her Hands (Box 143)
  - Predators and Ounces (Box 144)
  - Nasty Business (Box 144)
  - Untitled draft (Box 144)
  - Short fiction (Box 144)
  - Two or Three Things I Know For Sure draft and design (Box 145)
  - Not Poems - Polemic draft (Box 145)
  - Women's write columns and other essays (Box 145)
  - Non-fiction writing (Box 145)
  - Non-fiction (Box 145)
  - Cavedweller play script (Box 145)
  - Introduction to a deviant ethnography (Box 145)
  - Voices of feminism transcript (oral history interview with Dorothy Allison) (Box 145)
  - Skin draft (2 folders) (Box 146)
  - Skin proof (Box 146)
  - Untitled drafts (Box 146)
  - Cavedweller draft (Box 146)
  - Bastard Out of Carolina copy edited manuscript, with designer's markings (Box 147)
  - Journals, 1992-2008
    RESTRICTED: Access to Allison's journals are restricted and require her permission prior to use. Boxes 148-155 consist of computer printouts; boxes 156-163 are handwritten.
    - 1992-1996, 1999-2000 (Box 148)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 149)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 150)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 151)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 152)
    - 2005 (Box 153)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 154)
    - 2007-2009 (Box 155)
    - 1985-1989 (Box 156)
    - July 1989-January, 1993 (Box 157)
    - February, 1993-May, 1995 (Box 158)
    - May, 1995-February, 1997 (Box 159)
    - February, 1997-July, 1998 (Box 160)
    - July, 1998-October, 1999 (Box 161)
    - November, 1999-April, 2005 (Box 162)
    - January, 2006-February, 2008 (Box 163)
    - Undated, 2000s (Box 163)
- Audio/Visual Material Series, 1973-2004 and undated, (11 boxes)
  The material on the VHS tapes and DVDs consists of Allison's readings and other appearances. The audio cassettes contain material that mirrors the topics in Allison's subject files, including feminism and lesbian activism.
  - VHS tapes, 1990-2003 (Box 164)
  - VHS Tapes, 1991-2001 (Box 165)
  - Audio cassettes, 1975-1982 and undated (Box 166)
  - DVDs, 2001-2004 (Box 166)
  - VHS tapes, 2004 and undated (Box 166)
  - Audio cassettes, 1975-1983 and undated (Box 167)
  - Audio cassettes, 1981-1984 and undated (Box 168)
  - Audio cassettes, 1975-1982 and undated (Box 169)
  - Audio cassettes, 1983-1993 and undated (Box 170)
  - Photo album, 1965-1987 (Box 171)
  - Photo album, 1973-1975 (Box 172)
  - Posters and oversize materials, undated (Box 173)
  - Calendar, clippings and oversize materials, 1981-1996 and undated (Box 174)
- Oversize Materials
  - Miscellaneous Posters (Opaperfolder 1)